Charles Coleman Sellers Collection ca.1940-1978 Mss.Ms.Coll.3
American Philosophical Society
Charles Coleman Sellers Collection
Circa 1940-1978
Mss.Ms.Coll.3
American Philosophical Society
19.5 Linear feet
The collection of Charles Coleman Sellers (1903-1980) contains copious and detailed documentation of the art of Charles Willson Peale and his family. It consists of working files for Sellers's numerous publications, including his Portraits and Miniatures by Charles Willson Peale (1952); Charles Willson Peale with Patron and Populace (1969); C. W. Peale's Portraits of Washington (1951); Benjamin Franklin in Portraiture (1962); Mr. Peale's Museum (1980). Most files include photographs of the art work, notes on the piece, and correspondence with authorities or owners. Other series include one relating to the paintings of various other Peales, including Anna C., James, Mary Jane, Raphaelle, Rembrandt, Rubens, and Sarah Miriam, and a miscellaneous artist file, which includes the same type of material and information on many eighteenth- and nineteenth-century artists, including Thomas Eakins, George Healy, Robert Edge Pine, William Rush, Thomas Sully, Benjamin West, James Abbott McNeill Whistler, etc. There is a separate Sellers collection at Dickinson College, primarily personal in nature.
Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-1980
Bibliography
Sellers, Charles Coleman, "Charles Willson Peale's Portraits of Washington," Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin (February 1951). Call no.: 920 Pam. 133.
Sellers, Charles Coleman, Portraits and Miniatures by Charles Willson Peale, APS Transactions 42 (1952). Call no.: 506.73 Am4t
Sellers, Charles Coleman, Benjamin Franklin in Portraiture (New Haven: Yale, 1962). Call no.: B F85se.
Sellers, Charles Coleman, Charles Willson Peale with Patron and Populace, APS Transactions 59 (1969). Call no.: 506.73 Am4t
Sellers, Charles Coleman, Mr. Peale's Museum (N.Y.: Norton, 1980). Call no.: B P31se
Related Archival Materials note
Several collections of papers pertaining to the Peale Family are housed at the APS, and these have been issued as a microfiche set, Lillian B. Miller, ed., The Collected Papers of Charles Willson Peale and His Family (Millwood, N.Y.: Kraus Microform, 1980).
There is a Sellers collection at Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pa., primarily personal in nature.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the estate of Charles Coleman Sellers, 1980 (accession number 1980-276ms).
Scope and Contents note
The Sellers Collection consists of the working file of the historian, Charles Coleman Sellers, pertaining to his research on the artistic oevre of Charles Willson Peale and his family. The Collection is organized in seven series, corresponding roughly to Sellers's publications on the subject, plus a series containing general notes on other contemporary artists and a small miscellaneous correspondence file.
Series I Charles Willson Peale Portraits and Miniatures 7 linear feet
Series II Mr. Peale's Museum 3 linear feet
Series III Benjamin Franklin in Portraiture 0.5 linear feet
Series IV Washington Portraits 1 linear foot
Series V Paintings by the Peales 4 linear feet
Series VI Artist File 1 linear foot
Series VII Correspondence 1 linear foot
Series VIII Miscellaneous materials 19 items; 2.5 linear feet
Native American Images Note: Reprinted black and white photographs from the Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology at Harvard of Native American artifacts once held by Charles Willson Peale’s Philadelphia Museum. Some of the items include Plains and Northwestern Indian utensils, clothes and canoes of the early 1800s. Of note, Thomas Jefferson’s Indian collection including a peace pipe, a painted buffalo robe, Cree Indian dresses and an Indian hunting shirt worn by Captain Cook. Some later dated images, ca. 1840s, depict native Hawaiian and Caribbean objects. Primarily housed in Series II.
Biographical/Historical note
Charles Coleman Sellers (1903-1980) was a noted historian of early America, best known for his numerous works on the life and artistic production of the family of his own great-grandfather, Charles Willson Peale. Born in Overbrook, Pa., in 1903, Sellers attended Haverford College (1925) and Harvard (MA 1926), before taking a position as librarian at Wesleyan College (1937-1949) and, later, Dickinson College (1956-1968). For several years in the late 1940s, Sellers worked at the American Philosophical Society as Research Associate.
Sellers's numerous books and articles focused largely on the voluminous artistic output of the Peale family and on the Peale Museum, an important site in the early Republic for presenting natural history to the general public. Sellers also conducted research on Benjamin Franklin and others among the Peales' contemporaries. He was awarded the Bancroft Prize in 1970 for his work on Peale and was elected to membership in the APS in 1979. He died in 1980 while on a visit to Australia.
Eakins, Thomas, 1844-1916; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790; Healy, George Peter Alexander, 1813-1894; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Peale family; Peale, Anna Claypoole, 1791-1878; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827; Peale, James,1749-1831.; Peale, Mary Jane, 1827-1902; Peale, Raphaelle, 1774-1825; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865; Peale, Sarah Miriam, 1800-1885; Pine, Robert Edge, 1730?-1788; Rush, William, 1756-1833; Sully, Thomas, 1783-1872; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820; Whistler, James McNeill, 1834-1903; Art; Artists; Comanche Indians; Cree Indians; Crow Indians; Dakota Indians; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of North America--Great Lakes (North America); Indians of North America--Oklahoma; Indians of North America--Pacific Coast; Lewis and Clark Expedition (1804-1806); Mandan Indians; Northwest Coast Indians; Ojibwa Indians; Painters--United States; Photographs; Plains Indians; Tlingit Indians; Washington, George, 1732-1799--Portraits, caricatures, etc
- Series I. Charles Willson Peale Portraits & Miniatures (Box 1-14)
  - Abercrombie, Mrs. James. (Minature)
  - Adams, John
  - Aitken, Robert, and wife
  - Adlum, John
  - Arbuckle, James, family
  - Armand, Gen. Armstrong, William
  - Bailey, Francis, and wife
  - Baker, Hilary
  - Baldwin, William
  - Baltimore, Lord
  - Barlow, Joel
  - Barney, Joshua
  - Barry, John (James Peale?)
  - Barton, Benjamin Smith
  - Barton, William
  - Barton, Sarah Benezet
  - Bartram, John
  - Bartram, William
  - Bassett, Col. Burwell
  - Bayard, John, and wife
  - Baylor, George
  - Bedford, Gunning
  - Belestre, François Marie
  - Belfield
  - Bendiner minatures
  - Benezet, Elizabeth. See: Horsfield, Elizabeth Benezet
  - Benezet, Mary [Wood-Pitmore]
  - Benjamin, Col. Eyres
  - Bentalou, Paul
  - Berrett, Robert, and Lydia
  - Berryhill, John, and Elizabeth
  - Bethesda, 1821
  - Beveridge, David, and Mary Emlen
  - Biddle, Clement
  - Biddle, James
  - Biddle, Nicholas
  - Bingham, William
  - Birchall, James [C.W.Peale?]
  - Birkhead
  - Blake, Robert
  - Bland, Theodorick
  - Blaney, (Sully?)
  - Bloomfield, Joseph, and Mary McIlvaine
  - Blount, John Gray
  - Blount, William
  - Bogert, Cornelius J
  - Boller, Catharine
  - Bonapartes in Bordentown, New Jersey
  - Bordley, Elizabeth
  - Bordley, Henrietta Maria
  - Bordley, John Beale
  - Bordley, John Beale, artile, Pharos
  - Bordley, John Beale, Frederick Moore materials
  - Bordley, John Beale, landscape
  - Bordley, Thomas, and Matthias
  - Boudinot, Elias
  - Bourne, Sylvanus
  - Boy
  - Boy in kilts
  - Boy with flute - pastel
  - Bradford, Richard H
  - Bradford, William
  - Brent, Daniel Carroll (?)
  - Brewer, [baby]
  - Brewer, Mrs. Eleanor Maccubin
  - Brewer, Nicholas
  - Brewer, Nicholas (Sutherland)
  - Brice, Mrs.John
  - Brodhead, Daniel
  - Brown, Jacob
  - Brunot, Felix, and daughter, Louisa
  - Buckland, William
  - Buckley, Daniel
  - Bull
  - Burd, Edward
  - Burns, Mrs. G
  - Burr
  - Butler, Anthony
  - Cadwalader, John
  - Cadwalader, Lambert
  - Cadwalader,Thomas
  - Caldwell, Susanna (Mrs. McCutcheon)
  - Calhoun, John C
  - Callahan, John
  - Calvert, Charles
  - Cambray-Digny, Louis Antoine Jean Baptiste
  - Candlelight
  - Carré, Charles, and Jean-Thomas Carré
  - (Carroll, Charles?) - unknown
  - Carroll children
  - Carroll, Charles (barrister)
  - Carroll, Mrs. Charles
  - Carroll, James
  - Carroll, Nicholas
  - Carson, John
  - Carter children
  - Carey, Richard
  - Caton, Richard (?)
  - Charlton, Mrs. Francis M
  - Charlton, Richard
  - Chase, Mrs. Jeremiah Townley (Hester Baldwin)
  - Chase, Samuel
  - Chase, Mrs. Anne Baldwin
  - Chastellux
  - Clark, William
  - Clarke, Elijah (Wren)
  - Clarkson, Mrs. Catherine Floyd
  - Clarkson, Joseph (Du Simitiere?)
  - Clay, Henry
  - Claypoole, James
  - Claypoole, Mary Chambers
  - Clerc, Laurent
  - Clymer, George
  - Cochran, John
  - Cockey, John
  - Coddington, Elizabeth Fitz-Randolph
    Scope and Contents note
    ( see: Fitz-Randolph, Elizabeth)
  - Columbianum
  - Columbus, Christopher
  - Cooper, Thomas
  - Conservation
  - Cooper, Virginia
  - Corbin, Mrs. Richard
  - Cortez,Hernando
  - Court of Death (copy)
  - Courtenay, Edward
  - Covington, Leonard
  - Cox, John, and Esther
  - Coxe, John R
  - Craig, Mrs. Margaret M
  - Craik, James
  - Crawford, James, family
  - Crawford, William H
  - Crayon (Magazine)
  - Cropper, John
  - Cunningham, James
  - Custis, J P
  - Daffin, Mrs. Elinor Ennalls
  - Dagworthy, Mrs. Martha Cadwalader
  - Dalzell, Jane Loudon
  - Davie, William Richardson
  - Dean, Joseph
  - Dearborn, Henry
  - DeButts, John
  - Decatur, Stephen
  - De Haas, John Philip
  - Delozier, Daniel
  - Dent, John, and Sarah Marshall Dent, and Ann Herbert Dent
  - Dentistry
  - De Peyster
  - De Peyster, Abraham B
  - De Peyster, Anna
  - De Peyster, James, and Anna
  - De Peyster, John
  - De Peyster, John, and Elizabeth Haring De Peyster
  - De Peyster, Mrs.Margaret
  - De Peyster, William, Sr., and Margareta Roosevelt De Peyster (copies)
  - De Peyster, William, Jr., and Christiana Dally De Peyster
  - De Peyster, William, Jr. (minature)
  - De Peyster family
  - Dickinson, John
  - Dickinson, John, and Mary Norris Dickinson
  - Dixon, John, and Mrs. Rosanna Dixon and daughter
  - Donaldson, Andrew
  - Donaldson, Joseph
  - Dorsey, Nathan
  - Drawings
    - Annapolis from tower 1788 - Creek and trees.
    - Belfield sketches
    - Blackberry tour sketch book, 1824
    - Brandywine
    - Brandywine, c.180?-1809
    - Bridge, 1796-1797
    - Cannon, c.1779
    - Columbian Magazine, 1786-1790
    - Columbian Magazine 1789 frontispiece
    - Diary sketches
    - Dogs, c. 1785-1795
    - Draisiana, 1819
    - Eagle, 1806
    - Ferry 3 miles below Bristol, 1777?
    - Fireplace, 1797-1802
    - Hudson River, 1801
    - in letters
    - Lewis and Clark items
    - Map, 1776
    - Nature, c. 1803
    - Page monument, Nov.-Dec. 1809
    - 1813 sketch book
    - Skull of bison?
    - Skulls. Published, c.1816-1818
    - Universal Asylum vignette., 1790
  - Duer, Lady Catherine
  - Duffield, Benjamin
  - Dunlop, John (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Duportail, Louis Lebeque
  - Eakin, Samuel
  - Early still life
  - Eden, Robert
  - Edwards, Jonathan
  - Elisha restoring to life the Shunammite's son, after Benjamin West
  - Ellicott, Louisa McFadden
  - Elliott, Thomas
  - Engravings
    - Accident in Lombard Street
    - Richardson
    - Ticket
  - Ewing, John
  - Ewing, Maskell, and Jane Hunter Ewing
  - Falls of Schuylkill
  - Family (early painting?)
  - Febiger, Christian
  - Fell, William
  - Ferguson, Thomas Ladsom
  - Findley, William (Rembrandt Peale)
  - First paintings
  - Fishbourne, Benjamin
  - Fitzgerald, Thomas
  - Fitzhugh, William
  - Fitz-Randolph, Elizabeth [Mrs. Coddington?]
  - Fitzsimmons, Christopher, and Catherine Pritchard Fitzsimmons
  - Flags
  - Flower, Benjamin
  - Floyd, Miss
  - Forman, David, and wife, Elizabeth Lee
  - Forrest, Thomas
  - Forsyth, Robert
  - Fox, George
  - Frames
  - Francis, Emma (James Peale "Household")
  - Francis, Katherine
    See also: Francis, Emma [no Emma Francis exists]
  - Francis, Mrs. Anne Willing
  - Franklin, Benjamin
  - Franks, David Salisbury
  - Frisby, Mr. and Mrs.
  - Fullerton, Robert, and wife Mary Hall
  - Fulton, Robert (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Gadsden, Christopher (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Galbraith, Mrs.
  - Gano, Stephen
  - Gano miscellany
  - Gassaway, John
  - Gates, Horatio
  - Gelston, David, and wife
  - Gerard de Rayneval, Conrad Alexandre
  - Gibbs, Caleb
  - Gibbs, Richard and wife, Margery Harrison
  - Gignilliant, James, and wife, Charlotte Pepper
  - Gilmor, Robert, and wife
  - Girl with toy horse
  - Gist, Mordicai, and wife
  - Gittings, James, and wife, Elizabeth Buchanan
  - Glenn, James
  - Glentworth, George
  - Goldsborough, Mrs. Henrietta Maria Tilghman
  - Goldsborough, Mary Ann Turbot
  - Goldsborough, Robert, and family
  - Goldsborough, William
  - Goldsbury (Goldsborough), Samuel
  - Gorham, Nathaniel
  - Graeme, Thomas
  - De Grasse
  - Green, Ashbel
  - Green, Mrs. Anne Catherine
  - Green, Mrs. Anne Catherine Hoof
  - Green, Jonas, and wife
  - Greene, Nathanael
    See also: Washington
  - Grubb, Sarah
  - Grundy, Mrs.Mary Carr
  - Habersham, Joseph
  - Hackett, (not C.W.Peale)
  - Hake, Mrs. Eva Margareta Elizabeth De Peyster
  - Haley, Nathan (Vanderlyn)
  - Hall, Elihu, and wife Catherine Orrick
  - Hall, Mrs. Josias
  - Hall, Elizabeth and Catherine
  - Hallam, Nancy (Sarah)
  - Hamilton, Alexander
  - Hampton, Wade
  - Hancock, George, and wife, Margaret Strother
  - Hancock, John
  - Hanson, Alexander Contee
  - Hanson, John
  - Hare, Robert (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Harleston, John
  - Harris, David (Pine)
  - Harris, Thomas, and wife, Eleanor Davidson
  - Harrison, Benjamin, of Berkeley, and wife, Elizabeth Page
  - Harrison, Benjamin, Jr.
  - Hart
  - Harvey, Miss
  - Harwood, Mrs. Thomas (Margaret Strachan)
  - Haskins, Mrs. Sarah Barclay
  - Hay, George
  - Hazelwood
  - Hazlehurst, Robert
  - Head of a child
  - Head of a man (C.C.S.)
  - Heston, Mrs. John
  - Hewes, Joseph
  - Heyward, Thomas, Jr.
  - Hiester, Daniel
  - Hiester, Joseph
  - Hindman, Charles, and Mrs. Maria Campbell Ridgely
  - History of sources for C.W.Peale items
  - Hopkinson, Francis, and wife
  - Horsfield, Elizabeth Benezet
  - Howard, Charles
  - Howard, Hannah Few
  - Howard, John Eager
  - Howard, Mrs. Peggy Oswald Chew
  - Howell, Asher Mott (Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Howell, Joseph, Jr.
  - Hughes, Christopher
  - Humboldt, Alexander von
  - Hunt, Memucan, and wife ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Huntington, Samuel
  - Hutchinson, James
  - Hutson, Richard
  - Hutton, John Strangeways
  - Illustrations
  - Independent Club
  - Ingersoll, Jared
  - Inglis, John
  - Innis, Mrs. Rebecca Lewis
  - Innskeep, John (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Irvine, James
  - Irwin, Charles C (Benjamin Trott)
  - Jackson, Andrew
  - Jackson, Mrs. Hannah Tracy
  - Jackson, William
  - James, Charles C
  - Jay, John
  - Jay, John (James Peale?)
  - Jay, Peter Augustus
  - Jefferson, Thomas
  - Jenings, Edmund, III
  - Jennings, Thomas
  - Jessup, August E
  - Johnson, John, and brother
  - Johnson, Rinaldo
  - Johnson, Thomas, family
  - Johnson, Thomas (minature)
  - Johnson, Thomas, and wife
  - Jones, Gabriel (C.W.Peale?)
  - Jones, John Paul
  - Jones, Noble Wimberly
  - Josiah, James
  - Kalb, Baron de
  - Kauffman, Angelica
  - Keener, Melchior
  - Kerr, David, and wife, Mrs. Rachel Leeds Bozeman
  - Key, Philip, II
  - Key, Francis Scott
  - Kilby, William (Rembrandt Peale)
  - King, Rufus
  - King, William (C.W.Peale?)
  - Knox, Henry
  - Knox, Robert, and wife, Mrs. Sarah Hollingshead
  - Krebs, George Michael
  - Lady
  - Lady (Allis)
  - Lady (minature) John Elwyn Stone. (James Mease)
  - Lafayette
  - Laming, Benjamin, and wife, Mrs. Eleanor Ridgely
  - Lansdale, William Moylan (Bass Otis)
  - Landscapes
    - Belfield
    - Belfield (Parkinson-Levin
    - [C.W.Peale?]
    - Dressler
    - General
    - Moore House, 1805
    - Obelisk, 1813
    - Oil
    - Wayne (drawing)
    - "White House" Wilmer
  - Latimer, George
  - Latimer, James
  - Latrobe, Benjamin Henry
  - Laurens, Henry
  - Laurens, John
  - Lear, Tobias
  - Lee, Arthur
  - Lee, Billy
    See: Yarrow Mamout
  - Lee, Henry
  - Lee, Henry (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Lee,Richard Bland
  - Lee, Richard Henry
  - Legeré, Solomon (C.W.Peale?)
  - Lehman, Mrs. W E (J. Peale?)
  - Leiper, Mrs. Elizabeth Coultas Gray
  - Lesueur, Charles Alexandre
  - Levy, Moses and wife, Mrs. Mary Pearce Levy
  - Lewis, Addison
  - Lewis, John
  - Lewis, Meriwether
  - Lincoln, Benjamin
  - Linn, William (Jarvis)
  - List of portraits, 1770-1772
  - List of portraits
  - Livingston, Philip (??) Not C.W.Peale. (Del Drago)
  - Livingston, Robert
  - Livingston, Robert R
  - Lloyd, Edward
  - Lloyd, Richard
  - Lloyd, Richard Bennett
  - Lloyd family portraits (article)
  - Logan, Mrs. Deboarh Norris
  - Long, Stephen Harriman
  - Longueuil, Joseph Dominique Emmanuel Le Moyne de
  - Lotbiniere, Eustache Gaspard, sieur de
  - Lovett notes
  - Lowell, John
  - Lowndes, Christopher, and Mrs. Elizabeth Tasker
  - Lukens, Isaiah
  - Luzerne, Anne César de la
  - Lynn, David, and wife Mrs. Mary Galloway
  - McAllister, Mrs. John, Jr.
  - McClenachan, Blair
  - McComb, Eleazer
  - McElderry, Mr. and Mrs. (Eichholtz?)
  - McHenry, James, and wife Mrs. Margaret Caldwell
  - McIlvaine, Ferguson
  - McIntosh, Lachlan
  - Mackall, Mr. and Mrs. Benjamin
  - McKean, Thomas
  - Mackenzie, Thomas
  - Mackubbin, Charles Carroll
  - Mackubbin, Mrs. Charles Carroll
  - Mackubin, Mrs. James
  - McLane, Allan
  - Macpherson, Capt. and Mrs. John
  - Madison, James
  - Magellan, Fernando, (c. 1470-1521)
  - Maitland, Mrs. Susanna Poythress
  - Mamout, Yarrow
    See: Billy Lee
  - Man. American Art Association, 1916
    (Thaw-Vose)
  - Man. Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts
  - Man with a cane
  - Man with cane
  - Marshall, John (Ball Hughes)
  - Maryland Lady and man
  - Mason, George (Hesselius, 1754)
  - Mastodon, 1806
  - Matlack, Timothy
  - Maynard, Miss (James Peale)
  - Meade, George
  - Mease, James (Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Medals
  - Medford, Marmaduke
  - Medical
  - Meigs, Return Jonathan
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art. Unidentified portrait
  - Mifflin, Samuel, and wife Mrs. Rebecca Edghill
  - Mifflin, Thomas ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Miles, Samuel
  - Milledollar, Philip (James Peale and C.W.Peale?) and wife Mrs. Susan Benson
  - Miller, Elizabeth
  - Milligan, Mrs.
  - Miralles
  - Miscellany
  - Monroe, James
  - Montgomery, Mrs. James
  - Montgomery, Richard
  - Moore, Mrs. David (Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Moore, Frederick
    See: John Beale Bordley-Frederick Moore materials
  - Moore, Philip or James
  - Moore, Richard
  - Moore, William
  - Morgen, Daniel
  - Morris, Anthony
  - Morris, Gouverneur, and Robert
  - Morris, Mrs. Mary White
  - Morris, Olivia Simes (James Peale)
  - Morris, Phoebe Pemberton
  - Morris, Mrs. Rachel
  - Morris, Robert
  - Mosloy, Comte de
  - Moultrie, William
  - Muhlenberg, Frederick Augustus Conrad
  - Muhlenberg, Gotthilf Henry Ernest
  - Muhlenberg, Henry Melchior
  - Murray, Misses
  - Murray, William L
  - The Muse, 1762-1763
  - The Muse, 1764
  - Music
  - Music - Black box
  - Music illustrations
  - Music -"Lass of Richmond Hill" "Hush Ev'ry Breeze"
  - Music - Tobacco box
  - National Portrait Gallery Project
  - Nelson, Judith Page: Mrs. Hugh Nelson: and, Jane B. Nelson
  - Nevins, David (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Newell, Elisha
  - Nicholas, Samuel
  - Nichols, Francis
  - Nicholson, John
  - Nicholson, Joseph
  - Nicholson, Thomas
  - Nixon, John
  - Noah, 1819 Oct. 25-Dec. 11
  - North, William
  - Norvell, John
  - Nutz, Margaretha Keyser
  - O'Donnell, Mary
  - O'Donnell, Mrs.Sarah Chew Elliott
  - Ogle, Mrs. Benjamin
  - Onion, Thomas Bond, and wife
  - Paca, William
  - Page, John
  - Page, John, of Pagebrook
  - Paine, Thomas
  - Patten, John
  - Patten, Mr. and Mrs. William
  - Patterson Sister (Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Patterson, Mrs. Robert
  - Patterson, Mrs. Elizabeth De Peyster Peale
  - Peale, (photo)
  - Peale, (daughter of James Peale)
  - Peale, Charles Linnaeus, and wife
  - Peale, Charles Willson and Angelica and Rephaelle
  - Peale, Charles Willson
    - Artist in his museum
    - Bubbles
    - Drama
    - Grave - St. Peters
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellaneous portraits
    - Papers
    - Permissions
    - Self-portrait
    - Self-portrait in uniform
    - Self-portrait (Lewis)
    - Self-portrait, 1804
    - Self-portrait owned formerly by A.R.Peale
    - Self-portrait (Colton)
    - Self-portrait (R.P.B. Patterson)
    - Self-portrait (staircase, 1823
    - Self-portrait, 1824
    - by James Peale
    - by Rembrandt Peale
    - by Benjamin West
    - and Hannah ( not by C.W.Peale)
    - Walk...Philadelphia Museum
  - Peale, Mrs. Elizabeth De Peyster
  - Peale, Mrs. Elizabeth De Peyster(?) Valdenuil
  - Peale, Mrs. Hannah Moore
  - Peale, Mrs. Hannah Moore, 1816
  - Peale, Charles Willson (son of Rubens)
  - Peale, Mrs. Edmund
  - Peale, Mrs. Franklin
  - Peale, James
  - Peale, James, family
  - Peale, James (Pratt)
  - Peale, James 1822 Lamplight
  - Peale, James, and son
  - Peale, Mrs. Margaret Triggs
  - Peale, Mrs. Mary Claypoole
  - Peale, Rachel Brewer
  - Peale, Raphaelle, and Titian Ramsay (staircase)
  - Peale, Raphaelle
  - Peale, Rembrandt (photos)
  - Peale, Rembrandt, 1855
  - Peale, Rubens (by Rembrandt Peale, A.C.Peale, etc.)
  - Peale, Mrs.Rubens
  - Peale, St. George
  - Peale, Sophonisba and Linnaeus
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay II
  - Peale family
  - Pell, Charlotte Adams
  - Pendleton, Edmund
  - Pendleton, Mrs. Edmund (by??)
  - Penn, Sir William
  - Perkins, Jacob
  - Perry, Mr.
  - Perry, Oliver Hazard
  - Peters, Richard
  - Pettit, Charles
  - Physick, Edmund
  - Pickering, Timothy
  - Pillmore, Joseph
  - Pinckney, William
  - Pitt, William
  - Pitt, William (mezzotint)
  - Plater, George
  - Poe, Edgar Allen (by Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Polk, Elizabeth Digby Peale
  - Polk, Ruth Ellison
  - Polk, William
  - Porter, Andrew
  - Porter, David
  - Potts,Joseph (C.W. Peale??)
  - Poulson, Zachariah, and Susannah
  - Preble, Edward
  - Proctor, Ann, and Mary
  - Profiles
    - Greer pair (Raphael?)
    - Knox minatures (Raphael? Rembrandt?)
    - Kugler, George (Raphaelle?)
    - Peale, C. W. [!]
    - Peale, Rubens. (Raphaelle?)
    - Smith,William R J.Peale
  - Putnam, David, Sr.
  - Rachel weeping
  - Rachael weeping. Berger, Arthur
  - Rachel weeping - Restoration
  - Ramsay, David
  - Ramsay, Nathaniel
  - Ramsburgh, Polly (Mrs. Gilbert Middleton)
  - Randall, John
  - Randolph, Peyton
  - Randolph, Thomas Jefferson
  - Rawlins, Joseph Jr., and wife
  - Réal, Count
  - Red Jacket ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Reed, Mrs.Esther de Berdt
  - Reed, George Washington (Rembrandt)
  - Reed, Joseph
  - Reed, Seth
  - Richmond, Christopher
  - Ridgely, Mrs. Mary Wynkoop
  - Ridout, John
  - Riehlé, Margaretta
  - Rigauville, Jean Baptiste de Bergères
  - Ringgold, Thomas
  - Rittenhouse, David (U.of Pa.)
  - Rittenhouse, David (minature)
  - Rittenhouse, David
  - Rittenhouse, David (Trumbull)
  - Robinson, Alexander, and wife, Mrs. Angelica Peale
  - Roberts, Mrs. Mary Tilghman
  - Robinson, Mrs. Angelica Peale (Didier)
  - Robinson, Mrs. Angelica Peale
  - Robinson, Mrs. Angelica Peale and convalescent child
  - Robinson, Mrs.Anthony?
  - Robinson, Thomas
  - Rochambeau
  - Rodgers, John
  - Rodney, Caesar
  - Rogers, Joseph (by?)
  - Rogers, Nicholas
  - Rogers, Mrs. Rebecca
  - Rolfe, Charles (Rembrandt Peale?]
  - Rovin, John, and wife Mrs. Sarah
  - Rudulph, Michael
  - Rush, Anne Emily
  - Rush, Benjamin (copied from Sully)
  - Rush, Mrs. Mary Wrench
  - Russell, James
  - Russell, Thomas, and wife Mrs. Ann
  - Russell, William
  - Saint Clair, Arthur
  - Sansom, Joseph